# **Evermore Harmony Mwase**

I'm a holder of Bachelor's of Science in Computer Engineering . Currently working as IT support technician at Pixelfearie in Cape Town. I have 5 years experience in IT. I have proficient skills in both Software and Hardware management. I worked as IT specialist, Desktop Publisher, IT auditor, IT salesperson and numerator.

Cape Town, WC 7925 7925 mwase.evermore@gmail.com

+27 60 241 2775

I'm young man aged 25 with Bachelor's of Science in Computer Engineering. I have expertise in a variety of fields including Hardware Systems and Software management development both websites and mobile applications. Additionally, I have a great deal of experience with networking, databases and I can install, setup, and manage a variety of devices, such as computers, printers, and networking systems, in addition to troubleshooting network issues.

Currently, I'm working as an IT support technician at PixelFaerie in Cape Town, the same previous job I worked at Audit Consult in Malawi.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

# Work Experience

#### **IT Support Technician**

PixelFaerie-Cape Town, Western Cape August 2024 to Present

I'm working as IT support technician, where I offer support to the employees. Making sure everything related to IT is in order.

# **Desktop Publisher**

PixelFaerie-Cape Town, Western Cape March 2024 to July 2024

I'm working as Desktop Publisher our main task is to create quality slides using Power Point for our clients.

## IT Specialist

Audit Consult-Lilongwe June 2021 to December 2023

- i. Software Developer
- Developed Web application system that handles expenses, timesheets, engagements with the clients.
- ii. IT Support Specialist
- a. IT Support Specialist Responsibilities
- Installed and configured computer hardware, operating systems, and applications.
- Troubleshot system and network problems, diagnosing and resolving hardware and software faults.
- Confirmed all system software was correctly licensed and being used accordingly.
- Built and maintained good working relationships with colleagues across the business to increase IT support capabilities.
- b. System Performance and Maintenance
- Monitored and maintained the performance of company computers, network and systems, addressing issues.

- Supported the roll-out of new applications, providing space for users to ask questions and become familiar with features.
- Configured network systems and other computer systems including printers, servers.
- Resolved technical and application problems via helpdesk, both over the phone and in person.
- Performed set-up and maintenance of user systems with correct permissions to enable them to complete job roles and relevant tasks.
- c. Coordination and Documentation
- Prepared, organized, and coordinated IT support for client seminars, conferences, and other events.
- Provided timely and prompt responses to and resolutions for technology service issues and requests.
- Kept a detailed and accurate inventory of all local hardware and software, updating promptly and addressing missing information.

#### iii. IT Auditor

- a. System Monitoring and Assessment
- Monitored system performance to identify weaknesses, bottlenecks, and inefficiencies.
- Simulated system operation virtually to complete assessments and tests.
- Validated systems to assess needed improvements and recommended options for closing gaps and enhancing functionality.
- b. Technology Trends and Integration
- Tracked technology trends and researched potential integrations to meet functional or performance needs.
- Formulated functional specifications to support systems developers.
- c. Process Evaluation and Improvement
- Determined strengths and weaknesses of established processes and practices.
- Kept updated on advancements in the latest information system solutions.
- Gathered and defined user requirements for system updates.
- d. Project Management and Analysis
- Applied appropriate project management techniques to execute ICT projects successfully.
- Analysed the business's current work practices to recommend improvement actions.
- Created and deployed system testing plans to back up deployments.
- e. Data Testing and Data extraction
- Extracted data from different systems including database.
- Performed data cleaning for proper data testing for completeness, accuracy and integrity.
- f. Disaster and data recovery plan
- Verified if the data recovery plan is in place.
- Tested the recovered data.

#### **Numerator**

National Statistical Officer-Mzuzu, Nkhata-Bay September 2018 to October 2018

- Prepared and conducted interviews with relevant parties to obtain information required for research purposes.
- Exceeded manager expectations by continually collecting quality information and obtaining data before set deadlines.
- Encouraged household participation with census duties, providing assistance and explaining procedures.
- Met with research study participants to collect vital data and administer questionnaires.

• Undertook various survey types and data collection activities, facilitating classification and directional surveys at regular programmed sites.

## Education

# **Bachelor's of Science in Computer Engineering**

University of Livingstonia - Rumphi, Livingstonia September 2018 to June 2022

# Malawi National Examination Board in High School Certificate

St Augustine Secondary School - Mzuzu,Nkhata-Bay

September 2014 to May 2018

#### Skills

- Active Directory (3 years)
- Project Management Project delivery ( Presentation and Coordination, Service agreements and Data presentations ) (4 years)
- Programming Languages and Development Tools (Dart, PHP, C, C++, JavaScript, React, VS code, SQL, MySQL android studio, html, bootstrap, Laravel, python). (4 years)
- Soft Skills (Customer relations, Communication skills, Excellent timekeeping, Team-oriented, Analytical problem-solving, Clear communication, Focus group management and Interview management) (5 years)
- Microsoft Office (5 years)
- Network support (4 years)
- Microsoft Windows Server (4 years)
- Development Process and Methodologies (System development life cycle phases, System Development methodologies (Agile approach, Waterfall approach, Prototype, etc.)) (3 years)
- Computer networking (4 years)

#### Links

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkgJ9J-3OZVa6CWNI5na 0A